# RAVINDU SACHINTHA

## Software Engineer



## **PERSONAL**

A fast learner, a flexible team worker, a knowledge and experiences seeker in the Computer Science field and a friendly, sociable character who is with communication and project management skills.

I'm very interested in web based application development and research areas such as Distributed computing, Blockchain, Machine Learning, and Natural Language Processing.

## **CONTACT**



640 / 57, 2<sup>nd</sup> Kurana, Colombo Road, Negombo



077-2769963 / 031-2223189



ravindusachintha53@gmail.com



ravindusachintha.github.io



github.com/RavinduSachintha

in

linkedin.com/in/ravindu-sachintha

## COMPETENCIES

#### **PROFESSIONAL**

Problem solver and logical thinker | Teamwork |
Career-focused | Strong work ethic | Adaptable

#### **PERSONAL**

Flexible | Good communicator | Responsible |
Motivated | Collaborative learner

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Awarded at Codefest 2018 organized by Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT), selecting for the top 10 finalists
- Awarded at HaXmas 2018 organized by Rotaract Club of Informatics Institute of Technology (IIT), selecting for the top 10 finalists
- Awarded at HackX 2k18 organized by Faculty of Science, University of Kelaniya (UOK) for "MemoryMate", selecting for the top 10 finalists
- Participated in IEEEXtream 11.0 (2017)
   Team Elites, island rank: 122
- Awarded at ihack 4.0 organized by UCSC ISACA student group for "MemoryMate" mobile application, selecting for the top 25 finalists
- Awarded at CodeZilla 2018 inter university hackathon held by Mozilla Campus Club of Uva Wellassa University for "Hello" mobile application

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **LANGUAGES**

Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, BASH

#### **FRAMEWORKS**

Spring Boot, Angular CLI, NodeJS

#### **DATABASES**

MySQL, MongoDB, Firestore

#### **TOOLS & UTILITIES**

Git, Docker, Docker-compose, GCP

#### **OPERATING SYSTEMS & IDES**

Ubuntu, Arch-Linux, Windows VScode, IntelliJ IDEA, WebStorm

## PROJECT EXPERIENCE

## **EDUCORE** - AN ONLINE EDUCATION SYSTEM FOR INSTITUTIONS (Mar 2020 - Aug 2020 / GROUP)

A customizable online education system for managing students, teachers, sessions and other required information of institutions ( Java, Spring-boot, MySQL, Angular )

Contributions: Project designing, Back-end implementation, Online examination module

## SITHUMI TRADINGS - AN INVENTORY MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

(Feb 2019 - Mar 2019 / GROUP)

A standalone application for managing daily deliveries and analyze reports. ( JavaFx, SQLight, PDFBox library )

Contributions: Report generating module

#### **REVIEW ANALYSIS SYSTEM USING NLP**

(Jan 2019 - Feb 2019 / GROUP)

A web based application to analyze provided reviews by using natural language processing. (Laravel, HTML, Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript) Contributions: Client coordination, Review summarization module

## **EMENT** - A PROJECT MANAGING AND MENTORING PLATFORM ( Mar 2018 - Jan 2019 / GROUP )

A web based system for managing and mentoring open source projects. ( Angular, NodeJS, MySQL, Firebase )

Contributions: Scrum master, Administration module

## MEMORY MATE - MOBILE APPLICATION (Sep 2018 - Present / GROUP)

An intelligent mobile application for Alzheimer's Patients to remind their daily tasks. ( React Native, Firebase ,Dialog flow )  $\,$ 

Contributions: Project designing, Dialog flow integration

### **EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Open-source contributor and a project maintainer (github.com/FOSS-UCSC/FOSSALGO)
- A student member of Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) ( 2017 - 2018 )
- A member of the music orchestra in the "Reid Handaawa" event at UCSC (2018)
- A committee member of "fosscody-1.0" open source coding competition in 2018 for UCSC 1st year students.
- A member of the school Mathematics society (2010 2012)
- A member of the team which has won the 1st place at the all island inter school laboratory competition. (2014)

### **EDUCATION**

University of Colombo School of Computing 2017 - Present

**BSc.(Hons) in Computer Science** 

Current GPA : 3.33

Harischandra National College, Negombo

2015

#### **GCE Advanced Level (Physical Science)**

Z - score : 1.5592
Results : 3B
District : Gampaha

#### **TRAINING**

#### Research Assistant - Internship (Aug 2019 - Feb 2020)

Had been attached to the University of Colombo School of Computing on an assignment basis as a research intern in the project "Land Registration Blockchain for Sri Lanka - 2019/2020".

#### **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

## Distributed Computing | Blockchain | Middleware

Currently conducting a research for the final year of the University under the title of "Paxos Variants in Permissioned Distributed Ledgers" that is related to distributed computing and algorithms.

## **REFERENCES**

### Dr. D. N. Ranasinghe

**Senior Lecturer** 

University of Colombo School of Computing, UCSC Building Complex,

35, Reid Avenue, Colombo 07

Email: dnr@ucsc.cmb.ac.lk

#### Dr. M. D. R. N. Dayaratne

#### **Senior Lecturer**

University of Colombo School of Computing, UCSC Building Complex, 35, Reid Avenue, Colombo 07

Email: rnd@ucsc.cmb.ac.lk